<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Powershell Version 3 Ctp 2 on A Sysadmin, An SRE, and a DevOps Walk Into a Bar</title>
    <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/categories/powershell-version-3-ctp-2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Powershell Version 3 Ctp 2 on A Sysadmin, An SRE, and a DevOps Walk Into a Bar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://stevenmurawski.com/categories/powershell-version-3-ctp-2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell V3 – Auto-loading of Modules</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2012/01/01/powershell-v3-auto-loading-of-modules/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2012/01/01/powershell-v3-auto-loading-of-modules/</guid>
      <description>PowerShell V3 includes a new “feature” – Auto-loading of modules.
What Does It Do? Module discovery has been updated to make the exported commands for modules that are not loaded visible in a PowerShell session.
In Version 2, if you run Get-Module on a module that is not loaded but in your PSModulePath, you’ll get some metadata about the module, but nothing about the ExportedFunctions, ExportedCmdlets, ExportedAliases, or ExportedVariables.&amp;nbsp;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell V3 – Default Parameter Values</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2012/01/01/powershell-v3-default-parameter-values/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2012/01/01/powershell-v3-default-parameter-values/</guid>
      <description>PowerShell Version 3 introduces the concept of Default Parameter Values.
This allows you to specify a value for one or more parameters for one or more commands.
To implement this, you need to populate a new hashtable – $PSDefaultParameterValues
That Description is Not Helpful Let’s look at some examples -
First off, we can specify the value for a parameter for a specific command.&amp;#160; The pattern used for the hashtable entries is “NameOfCommand:NameOfParameter” = “ValueOfParameter”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Import-Module Does Not</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2012/01/01/when-import-module-does-not/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2012/01/01/when-import-module-does-not/</guid>
      <description>A question came up about the behavior of what’s that?).
So What’s the Question? Does the auto-loading of modules in PowerShell Version 3 use Import-Module behind the scenes?&amp;#160; If it does, can we use default parameter sets to control what types of things are imported?
What Actually Happens? So, it turns out that default parameter set (new feature) can be used to customize the import of new modules.
$PSDefaultParameterValues = @{ &amp;quot;Import-Module:Alias&amp;quot;=@() &amp;quot;Import-Module:Function&amp;quot;=&amp;rsquo;&amp;lsquo; &amp;quot;Import-Module:Cmdlet&amp;quot;=&amp;rsquo;&amp;lsquo; &amp;quot;Import-Module:Variable&amp;quot;=&amp;rsquo;*&amp;rsquo; } Get-Module Get-BitsTransfer Get-Module</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>