<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2012 on A Sysadmin, An SRE, and a DevOps Walk Into a Bar</title>
    <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/categories/2012/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2012 on A Sysadmin, An SRE, and a DevOps Walk Into a Bar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://stevenmurawski.com/categories/2012/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>LISA 2012–Now with more PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2012/11/01/lisa-2012now-with-more-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2012/11/01/lisa-2012now-with-more-powershell/</guid>
      <description>The 2012 LISA (Large Installation System Administration) Conference is coming up (December 9-14).
If you aren’t familiar with LISA, it is a conference focusing on systems administration topics with a rich history (this is the 26th one).&amp;#160; There are 47 different full or half-day classes to choose from, as well as three days of additional technical sessions across three main themes – Cloud Computing, Super Sysadmin, and IPv6 and DNSSEC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Server 2012 in 31 Days–Recap</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2012/11/01/server-2012-in-31-daysrecap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2012/11/01/server-2012-in-31-daysrecap/</guid>
      <description>My friend Microsoft IT Pro Evangelist Brian Lewis (twitter, blog) contacted me about a series he, Matt Hester, Keith Mayer, and Kevin Remde were going to do through the month of October on their favorite things in Server 2012.&amp;#160;
&amp;#160;
My first thought was that a month was not enough, since Server 2012 is chock full of new goodness.&amp;#160; I watched the series develop and added my own meager contribution on what I think is the killer feature in Server 2012 – SMB3 and Continuously Available File Shares.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Still Time For Early Bird Registration For LISA 2012</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2012/11/01/still-time-for-early-bird-registration-for-lisa-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2012/11/01/still-time-for-early-bird-registration-for-lisa-2012/</guid>
      <description>SAVE THE DATE
LISA &amp;lsquo;12: 26th Large Installation System Administration Conference
December 9-14, 2012, San Diego, CA
https://www.usenix.org/lisa12
Early Bird Registration Deadline: November 19, 2012
Sponsored by USENIX in cooperation with LOPSA
LISA is coming to San Diego, CA, December 9-14, 2012. As always, the breadth and quality of this year&amp;rsquo;s tutorials, paper presentations, invited talks, and participants are excellent. Learn more at https://www.usenix.org/lisa12.
New for 2012 are themes, which allow you to follow a specific topic through tutorials, workshops, technical sessions, and the refereed papers track.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Server 2012–Continuously Available File Shares</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2012/10/01/server-2012continuously-available-file-shares/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2012/10/01/server-2012continuously-available-file-shares/</guid>
      <description>I think SMB3 and the enhancements to the clustered file share roles are some of the most important new features in Server 2012.
&amp;#160;
There are some great new features in file shares and the SMB protocol.&amp;#160; Some of the terminology can be confusing, so I’m going to loosely define a few of them right up front.
**SMB3 – **Revised SMB protocol with improved performance, scaling, and support for technology like RSS and RDMA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell at PICC</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2012/05/01/powershell-at-picc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2012/05/01/powershell-at-picc/</guid>
      <description>I had a great time with my classes at PICC.&amp;#160; Both the PowerShell Fundamentals class and the PowerShell Tips and Tricks class were a lot of fun and resulted in great conversations at the breaks and after the classes.
The fun continued in the evening with the Bird of a Feather sessions where we spent some time talking about Server 2012, Server Core, and remote server management.&amp;#160; What a great time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Games Are Afoot!</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2012/04/01/the-games-are-afoot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2012/04/01/the-games-are-afoot/</guid>
      <description>The Scripting Games that is! This year’s games are in progress, but it’s not too late to start.&amp;#160; Each weekday a new event is posted, but you have a week to turn in your solution, so get out there and start writing some PowerShell.
All the details you need are available from the Scripting Games All In One Links Page, where the Scripting Guy Ed Wilson has thoughtfully provided (and updates daily) links to the events, rules, and other great information.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>