<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Systems Administration on A Sysadmin, An SRE, and a DevOps Walk Into a Bar</title>
    <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/categories/systems-administration/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Systems Administration on A Sysadmin, An SRE, and a DevOps Walk Into a Bar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://stevenmurawski.com/categories/systems-administration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Server 2012 in 31 Days–Recap</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2012/11/01/server-2012-in-31-daysrecap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2012/11/01/server-2012-in-31-daysrecap/</guid>
      <description>My friend Microsoft IT Pro Evangelist Brian Lewis (twitter, blog) contacted me about a series he, Matt Hester, Keith Mayer, and Kevin Remde were going to do through the month of October on their favorite things in Server 2012.&amp;#160;
&amp;#160;
My first thought was that a month was not enough, since Server 2012 is chock full of new goodness.&amp;#160; I watched the series develop and added my own meager contribution on what I think is the killer feature in Server 2012 – SMB3 and Continuously Available File Shares.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Server 2012–Continuously Available File Shares</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2012/10/01/server-2012continuously-available-file-shares/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2012/10/01/server-2012continuously-available-file-shares/</guid>
      <description>I think SMB3 and the enhancements to the clustered file share roles are some of the most important new features in Server 2012.
&amp;#160;
There are some great new features in file shares and the SMB protocol.&amp;#160; Some of the terminology can be confusing, so I’m going to loosely define a few of them right up front.
**SMB3 – **Revised SMB protocol with improved performance, scaling, and support for technology like RSS and RDMA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back on RunAs Radio</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2012/06/01/back-on-runas-radio/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2012/06/01/back-on-runas-radio/</guid>
      <description>Richard Campbell was kind enough to have me back on RunAs Radio to talk about SMB3 and Scale-Out File Shares in Windows Server 2012.&amp;#160; We didn’t really talk about anything PowerShell related, but SMB3 and Scale-Out File Shares are a radical topic and are changing my data center deployments in a very good way.&amp;#160; Richard is a super smart guy and always drives the conversation in interesting directions, bringing out points that might have passed by and offering interesting insights that really make you think.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RunAs Radio and PowerShell V3</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2012/05/01/runas-radio-and-powershell-v3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2012/05/01/runas-radio-and-powershell-v3/</guid>
      <description>I joined Richard Campbell, the host of Runas Radio to talk about PowerShell V3 and Server 2012.&amp;#160; We had a great conversation and covered some of the improvements and new features in PowerShell V3 and the new cmdlets and support in Server 2012.
What’s RunAs Radio? RunAs Radio is a weekly internet audio talk show for IT professionals focused on Microsoft products.&amp;#160; They cover a full range of topics from a Microsoft-centric view point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell Modules for the SysAdmin</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2011/02/01/powershell-modules-for-the-sysadmin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2011/02/01/powershell-modules-for-the-sysadmin/</guid>
      <description>Now that I’m back working as a SysAdmin, I’ve come to live in Powershell (even more than I was already)&amp;hellip; I regularly have 4 or more console windows open at any one time, plus the ISE.
There are several modules that just make my work much more accessible from the command prompt rather than digging into a GUI or RDP’ing to a server.
ActiveDirectory – The Active Directory module included with the Win7 RSAT or the RSAT on Server 2008 R2</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dear Devs,  Give Us The Tools.  K Thx</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/07/01/dear-devs-give-us-the-tools-k-thx/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/07/01/dear-devs-give-us-the-tools-k-thx/</guid>
      <description>I just finished listening to the latest Herding Code podcast (#52) where the hosts (K. Scott Allen, Kevin Dente, Scott Koon, and Jon Galloway) talked with Alan Stevens ( C# MVP and ASP Insider) and G. Andrew Duthie (author and Microsoft Developer Evangelist) about a debate that began on Twitter regarding “Real Software Development vs Microsoft Bubble Development”. What does that have to do with PowerShell and administrative tools? The specifics of their conversation don’t have a lot of relevance to administrators and scripters, but one of the directions that their conversation took really resonated with me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Response: Give Me A Coconut and Six Months</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/06/01/response-give-me-a-coconut-and-six-months/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/06/01/response-give-me-a-coconut-and-six-months/</guid>
      <description>I was tagged by SQL Server Expert Brent Ozar in his response to a great, thought provoking blog post called Give Me a Coconut and Six Months by Tim Ford (SQLAgentMan on Twitter).
The short summary of the post is if you had six months free of distraction, what would you turn your attention to.&amp;#160; Tim’s choices included backups, security, and monitoring, which I think is a great “solid foundation” to work from.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing Database Schemas</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/02/01/comparing-database-schemas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/02/01/comparing-database-schemas/</guid>
      <description>I regularly am working with several versions of a database for an application that I manage (a live database, training database, test database, and previous version database).&amp;#160; Occasionally, I need to know what the differences between the databases are, especially after our vendor updates my test environment or right after an update in my training or live environment.&amp;#160;
Since I spend a good portion of my day in PowerShell, I wrapped some system table queries in a PowerShell script and use Compare-Object to find any differences in the tables and compare the column definitions as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dealing with WMI Timeouts</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/01/01/dealing-with-wmi-timeouts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/01/01/dealing-with-wmi-timeouts/</guid>
      <description>There was a question in the PowerShellCommunity.Org forums about WMI timeouts.
I did some digging and found there are several different types of timeouts that can affect your WMI queries.&amp;#160; I’m still working through different scenarios and I’d appreciate any feedback.
The first type of timeout can occur if the machine that you are targeting does not respond to network traffic (it’s down, you have the wrong IP address, firewalled, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>