<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Events on A Sysadmin, An SRE, and a DevOps Walk Into a Bar</title>
    <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/categories/events/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Events on A Sysadmin, An SRE, and a DevOps Walk Into a Bar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://stevenmurawski.com/categories/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>LISA 2012–Now with more PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2012/11/01/lisa-2012now-with-more-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2012/11/01/lisa-2012now-with-more-powershell/</guid>
      <description>The 2012 LISA (Large Installation System Administration) Conference is coming up (December 9-14).
If you aren’t familiar with LISA, it is a conference focusing on systems administration topics with a rich history (this is the 26th one).&amp;#160; There are 47 different full or half-day classes to choose from, as well as three days of additional technical sessions across three main themes – Cloud Computing, Super Sysadmin, and IPv6 and DNSSEC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Still Time For Early Bird Registration For LISA 2012</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2012/11/01/still-time-for-early-bird-registration-for-lisa-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2012/11/01/still-time-for-early-bird-registration-for-lisa-2012/</guid>
      <description>SAVE THE DATE
LISA &amp;lsquo;12: 26th Large Installation System Administration Conference
December 9-14, 2012, San Diego, CA
https://www.usenix.org/lisa12
Early Bird Registration Deadline: November 19, 2012
Sponsored by USENIX in cooperation with LOPSA
LISA is coming to San Diego, CA, December 9-14, 2012. As always, the breadth and quality of this year&amp;rsquo;s tutorials, paper presentations, invited talks, and participants are excellent. Learn more at https://www.usenix.org/lisa12.
New for 2012 are themes, which allow you to follow a specific topic through tutorials, workshops, technical sessions, and the refereed papers track.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell at PICC</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2012/05/01/powershell-at-picc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2012/05/01/powershell-at-picc/</guid>
      <description>I had a great time with my classes at PICC.&amp;#160; Both the PowerShell Fundamentals class and the PowerShell Tips and Tricks class were a lot of fun and resulted in great conversations at the breaks and after the classes.
The fun continued in the evening with the Bird of a Feather sessions where we spent some time talking about Server 2012, Server Core, and remote server management.&amp;#160; What a great time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Games Are Afoot!</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2012/04/01/the-games-are-afoot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2012/04/01/the-games-are-afoot/</guid>
      <description>The Scripting Games that is! This year’s games are in progress, but it’s not too late to start.&amp;#160; Each weekday a new event is posted, but you have a week to turn in your solution, so get out there and start writing some PowerShell.
All the details you need are available from the Scripting Games All In One Links Page, where the Scripting Guy Ed Wilson has thoughtfully provided (and updates daily) links to the events, rules, and other great information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Want to PICC up some new skills?</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2012/04/01/want-to-picc-up-some-new-skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2012/04/01/want-to-picc-up-some-new-skills/</guid>
      <description>If you are out on the East Coast and want to pick up some new skills or freshen up some old ones, check out PICC – the Professional IT Community Conference.
PICC is hosted in New Brunswick, New Jersey and is two days of great SysAdmin content (May 11&amp;frasl;12).
You’ll find half day training sessions on things like:  PowerShell (by your truly) Puppet Time Management Technical Resume Writing IPv6 Workplace Presentations and more…  There are also conference sessions on topics like:  Ganeti (Virtualization Management Platform) Windows Deployment with MDT 2010 Scaling the StackExchange Platform Configuration Management Securing MySQL Deep Application Monitoring and more…  I’ll be there, and I’m definitely going to walk away better prepared to do my job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cascadia Community Conference - 2012</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2012/03/01/cascadia-community-conference-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2012/03/01/cascadia-community-conference-2012/</guid>
      <description>I had a great time at the Cascadia conference this past weekend.&amp;#160; I missed Friday, but got to spend all day Saturday teaching PowerShell to a great group of attendees.&amp;#160; There were some great questions and interesting thoughts developed in both the Fundamentals class and the Tips and Tricks class.
I want to thank the organizers of the conference for having me out and especially to the attendees for my classes, most of whom spent all day with me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources for the WI .NET User Group</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2011/09/01/resources-for-the-wi-net-user-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2011/09/01/resources-for-the-wi-net-user-group/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll get the slides posted sometime (in the middle of migrating my machine to the developer preview of Win 8), but the links I mentioned are:
—Project Home - http://www.show-ui.com
—CodeplexSite - http://showui.codeplex.com
—Doug Finke’s Blog - http://dougfinke.com/blog
—Joel “Jaykul” Bennet’sBlog - http://huddledmasses.org
—James Brundage’sBlog - http://blog.start-automating.com/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where I’ll be this Fall</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2011/09/01/where-ill-be-this-fall/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2011/09/01/where-ill-be-this-fall/</guid>
      <description>I wish I could have make it out to Build or the PowerShell Deep Dive, but I’ll settle for these:
 September 13th – Wisconsin .NET User Group – Talking about Scriptable UI with PowerShell and ShowUI September 29th – Greater Milwaukee IT Pro User Group – Talking about the PsTools in the Sysinternals Suite October 1st – SQL Saturday #98 (Iowa City, IA) – Talking about Scriptable UI with PowerShell and ShowUI November 1st – LaCrosse IT Pro User Group – Going over an Introduction to PowerShell  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get in the Games!</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2011/04/01/get-in-the-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2011/04/01/get-in-the-games/</guid>
      <description>This year’s Scripting Games is well underway, but there is still time to get involved.
You can submit entries for 7 days after an event was released, so there is still time to participate.&amp;#160;
Definitely Fun, Not all Games… If you think that the games are just that, think again.&amp;#160; If you are just getting in to PowerShell, the events cover many practical applications.
Beginner Event 1 Identifying Private Builds – Stresses finding information about running processes or executables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time to Start Ramping Up for the Scripting Games</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2011/03/01/time-to-start-ramping-up-for-the-scripting-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2011/03/01/time-to-start-ramping-up-for-the-scripting-games/</guid>
      <description>The 2011 Scripting Games are fast approaching (April 4th through the 15th)..
If you’ve been holding off on learning a bit a PowerShell, now is the time to step up and try some of these events.&amp;#160; Ed Wilson put together a study guide to help prepare you for some of the skills and techniques you will exercise.
If you have participated before, this year promises to be as fun and exciting, if not more so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell Deep Dive–Last Call for Early Registration</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2011/02/01/powershell-deep-divelast-call-for-early-registration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2011/02/01/powershell-deep-divelast-call-for-early-registration/</guid>
      <description>The first ever PowerShell Deep Dive conference is coming up in April (18-19).&amp;#160; I&amp;rsquo;m thrilled to be going.&amp;#160; Early registration for the conference ends on 2&amp;frasl;28 (just a day away), so save yourself $150 and register today!
You can find more details about the structure of the event and a pre-conference workshop by Don Jones (to make sure you are up to speed for the Deep Dive) here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring 2011</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2011/02/01/spring-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2011/02/01/spring-2011/</guid>
      <description>Spring 2011 is shaping up to be a busy time…
March 9th – I’ll be at the Black Hole .NET User Group (in Marshfield, WI) for an Introductory PowerShell For Developers Presentation.
March 26th – I’m going to SQL Saturday in Chicago.&amp;#160; I’ve submitted a couple of sessions (PowerShell Basics and Intermediate PowerShell), so I should know if one get’s accepted towards the end of this month.&amp;#160; Regardless, I’m planning on attending.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TechMentor Approaching Fast!</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2011/02/01/techmentor-approaching-fast/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2011/02/01/techmentor-approaching-fast/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;rsquo;re not too late for TechMentor Orlando, March 14 - 18, 2011 at Disney&amp;rsquo;s Yacht Club.
TechMentor is offering Use PowerShell readers the best discount so far - $400 discount off the 5 Day Best Value Conference Pass (discount applies to the Standard rate and new registrations only)! Register at http://bit.ly/TMReg with the code UGTM10 for the discount.
If you&amp;rsquo;ve never attended it, TechMentor is 5 intensive and informative days of immediately-applicable training on today&amp;rsquo;s critical IT topics - everything from Active Directory to Virtualization - with a specific track and several sessions on PowerShell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lake County .NET Users Group–Slide Deck and Samples</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2010/11/01/lake-county-net-users-groupslide-deck-and-samples/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2010/11/01/lake-county-net-users-groupslide-deck-and-samples/</guid>
      <description>Scott Seely and Tim Stall invited me to give an introduction to PowerShell talk for the Lake County .NET Users Group yesterday evening.
We had a great turnout and a number of good questions.&amp;#160; Thank you to everyone who gave up part of their evening to come and learn a bit about the .NET command shell goodness that is PowerShell.&amp;#160;
I’ve uploaded the slide deck, sample scripts, and sample Visual Studio solution here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New IT Pro User Group In Milwaukee</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2010/09/01/new-it-pro-user-group-in-milwaukee/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2010/09/01/new-it-pro-user-group-in-milwaukee/</guid>
      <description>Come Join the Greater Milwaukee Information Technology Professional User Community (GMITPUC). We will be having our first meeting will be September 29, 2010 @ the Waukesha, Microsoft office, N19 W24133 Riverwood Drive, Suite 150, Waukesha, WI 53188 Starting at 6:00 PM
The presentation for the evening will be presented by Brian Lewis an IT Pro Evangelist from Microsoft Corporation. He will be covering Windows 7 and Office 2010 Deployment. Here is the agenda: · How to upgrade from XP to Widows 7</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerScripting Podcast – New Night (temporary change)</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/05/01/powerscripting-podcast-new-night-temporary-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/05/01/powerscripting-podcast-new-night-temporary-change/</guid>
      <description>For the next month or two, the PowerScripting Podcast will be live on Tuesday nights at 9 PM Eastern / 8 PM Central.&amp;#160; Be sure to update your calendars and stop in for some great, interactive PowerShell content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WI VMUG Presentation with Scott Herold</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/05/01/wi-vmug-presentation-with-scott-herold/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/05/01/wi-vmug-presentation-with-scott-herold/</guid>
      <description>This morning, Scott Herold and I did back to back presentations on PowerShell and the Virtualization EcoShell for the Wisconsin VMWare Users Group. Time flew by and I didn’t get to the second half of my slide deck, so if you are interested, here it is.
If you want to see the webcast, you can find it here. Just a word of warning, I haven’t listened to it yet, but we were recording over Skype and a fixed microphone while speaking over another mic in a larger room.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell, VMWare, and VESI in Wisconsin</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/04/01/powershell-vmware-and-vesi-in-wisconsin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/04/01/powershell-vmware-and-vesi-in-wisconsin/</guid>
      <description>On May 19th, Scott Herold and I will be presenting for the Wisconsin VMWare Users Group. I&amp;rsquo;ll be covering the basics of PowerShell, as well as an introduction to the VI Toolkit (for Windows)/PowerCLI.
Scott will be talking about the Virtualization EcoShell Initiative (VESI).
If you are in Wisconsin, the meeting details can be found here.
If you are not able to make the meeting, VMWare will be providing a live stream of our presentations via WebEx, as well as providing recordings after the fact.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShellCommunity.Org goes to TechEd</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/04/01/powershellcommunityorg-goes-to-teched/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/04/01/powershellcommunityorg-goes-to-teched/</guid>
      <description>This year at TechEd (North America), Hal Rottenberg and I will be there promoting PowerShell and PowerShellCommunity.Org. We will be bouncing around various sessions, the PowerShell booth, and the remaining conference. If you have a PowerShell story that you want to share, find me (I&amp;rsquo;m a big guy and easy to pick out of a crowd). I&amp;rsquo;ll have some recording gear and be looking to collect some user stories.
See you there!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Busy Week Ahead!</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/03/01/busy-week-ahead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/03/01/busy-week-ahead/</guid>
      <description>Monday, I’ll be delivering an Introduction to PowerShell presentation at Brainstorm (a conference for IT Pro’s supporting K-12 schools).&amp;#160;
On Tuesday, I’ll be delivering a presentation to the local .NET Users Group focused more towards developing with PowerShell.&amp;#160;
I’ll also have this week’s Exploring the .NET Framework post on static methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft TechDays Virtual Event</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/03/01/microsoft-techdays-virtual-event/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/03/01/microsoft-techdays-virtual-event/</guid>
      <description>On April 1st, 2009, Microsoft is putting on a free 24 hour virtual event covering developer-related topics. There will be 95 live sessions provided via Live Meeting in the following tracks:
 Windows Development and Frameworks Windows Mobile Development Office and SharePoint Development Developer Tools, Languages &amp;amp; Practices Web Development &amp;amp; User Experience  PowerShell Community’s own Marco Shaw (MVP) will be presenting the ONLY PowerShell session:
  WIN300 Scripting the Microsoft .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calling all Ohio PowerShell Enthusiasts!</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/01/01/calling-all-ohio-powershell-enthusiasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/01/01/calling-all-ohio-powershell-enthusiasts/</guid>
      <description>The Central Ohio Day of .NET is coming up (April 18th, 2009) and they’ve put out a request for speakers.&amp;#160; From their website:
  The Central Ohio Day of .NET is a joint venture between the Dayton .NET Developers Group, Central Ohio .NET Developers Group, Cincinnati SQL Server Users Group and the Cincinnati .NET Users Group.
Why don’t we get some PowerShell related sessions added to the lineup.&amp;#160; They said specifically that they are looking for introductory material on new technologies.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>