<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Powershell Community on A Sysadmin, An SRE, and a DevOps Walk Into a Bar</title>
    <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/categories/powershell-community/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Powershell Community on A Sysadmin, An SRE, and a DevOps Walk Into a Bar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://stevenmurawski.com/categories/powershell-community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Back on the PowerScripting Podcast</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2012/05/01/back-on-the-powerscripting-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2012/05/01/back-on-the-powerscripting-podcast/</guid>
      <description>You think Hal and Jonathan would learn, but they keep having me back on the show.
Hal was out of town, but Jon and I had a great talk about Server 2012 and PowerShell V3.&amp;#160; As always, there was great conversation in the chat room and some good questions.&amp;#160; Jon had a surprise for us all.&amp;#160; After the interview, he played Jeffrey Snover’s keynote from the PowerShell Deep Dive.&amp;#160;
Check out this episode and the other great shows and interviews they have.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Games Are Afoot!</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2012/04/01/the-games-are-afoot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2012/04/01/the-games-are-afoot/</guid>
      <description>The Scripting Games that is! This year’s games are in progress, but it’s not too late to start.&amp;#160; Each weekday a new event is posted, but you have a week to turn in your solution, so get out there and start writing some PowerShell.
All the details you need are available from the Scripting Games All In One Links Page, where the Scripting Guy Ed Wilson has thoughtfully provided (and updates daily) links to the events, rules, and other great information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I’m on TechNet Radio!</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2011/07/01/im-on-technet-radio/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2011/07/01/im-on-technet-radio/</guid>
      <description>A little while back, I had an opportunity to talk with John Weston on TechNet Radio’s Community Corner.
We talked a bit about PowerShell and the community around it, as well as my local Script Club.
&amp;#160;

&amp;#160;
Thanks to John and Chris for taking the time to talk with me, and don’t forget to check out the other great segments in the Community Corner and see what is happening in other user groups!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Round up</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2011/04/01/round-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2011/04/01/round-up/</guid>
      <description>Just some odds and ends from the week -
 Blog post and script from James Brundage on converting scripts, functions, or cmdlets into executables. The Scripting Games are underway. My session on Building a Management API with PowerShell for the Chicago Code Camp was accepted. Andy Schneider had a great post about modules. Jeff Hicks helps us clear aliases from our scripts (in the ISE). Doug Finke shows us how to use Excel math functions in PowerShell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time to Start Ramping Up for the Scripting Games</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2011/03/01/time-to-start-ramping-up-for-the-scripting-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2011/03/01/time-to-start-ramping-up-for-the-scripting-games/</guid>
      <description>The 2011 Scripting Games are fast approaching (April 4th through the 15th)..
If you’ve been holding off on learning a bit a PowerShell, now is the time to step up and try some of these events.&amp;#160; Ed Wilson put together a study guide to help prepare you for some of the skills and techniques you will exercise.
If you have participated before, this year promises to be as fun and exciting, if not more so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring 2011</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2011/02/01/spring-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2011/02/01/spring-2011/</guid>
      <description>Spring 2011 is shaping up to be a busy time…
March 9th – I’ll be at the Black Hole .NET User Group (in Marshfield, WI) for an Introductory PowerShell For Developers Presentation.
March 26th – I’m going to SQL Saturday in Chicago.&amp;#160; I’ve submitted a couple of sessions (PowerShell Basics and Intermediate PowerShell), so I should know if one get’s accepted towards the end of this month.&amp;#160; Regardless, I’m planning on attending.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Script Club – Coming to the Greater Milwaukee Area</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/12/01/script-club-coming-to-the-greater-milwaukee-area/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/12/01/script-club-coming-to-the-greater-milwaukee-area/</guid>
      <description>Register here. About PowerShell Script Club  You Always Talk About Script club 2. You Always Talk About Script Club 3. If Someone asks for Help, And You Can Help, You Help 4. Two People Help One Person at One Time 5. One Module Per Person Per Night 6. All Scripts, All PowerShell 7. Scripts will be as short as they can be 8. If This is your First time at Script Club, You Have to Script  The first Greater Milwaukee PowerShell Script Club is being formed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerScripting Podcast – New Night (temporary change)</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/05/01/powerscripting-podcast-new-night-temporary-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/05/01/powerscripting-podcast-new-night-temporary-change/</guid>
      <description>For the next month or two, the PowerScripting Podcast will be live on Tuesday nights at 9 PM Eastern / 8 PM Central.&amp;#160; Be sure to update your calendars and stop in for some great, interactive PowerShell content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell, VMWare, and VESI in Wisconsin</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/04/01/powershell-vmware-and-vesi-in-wisconsin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/04/01/powershell-vmware-and-vesi-in-wisconsin/</guid>
      <description>On May 19th, Scott Herold and I will be presenting for the Wisconsin VMWare Users Group. I&amp;rsquo;ll be covering the basics of PowerShell, as well as an introduction to the VI Toolkit (for Windows)/PowerCLI.
Scott will be talking about the Virtualization EcoShell Initiative (VESI).
If you are in Wisconsin, the meeting details can be found here.
If you are not able to make the meeting, VMWare will be providing a live stream of our presentations via WebEx, as well as providing recordings after the fact.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft TechDays Virtual Event</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/03/01/microsoft-techdays-virtual-event/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/03/01/microsoft-techdays-virtual-event/</guid>
      <description>On April 1st, 2009, Microsoft is putting on a free 24 hour virtual event covering developer-related topics. There will be 95 live sessions provided via Live Meeting in the following tracks:
 Windows Development and Frameworks Windows Mobile Development Office and SharePoint Development Developer Tools, Languages &amp;amp; Practices Web Development &amp;amp; User Experience  PowerShell Community’s own Marco Shaw (MVP) will be presenting the ONLY PowerShell session:
  WIN300 Scripting the Microsoft .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calling all Ohio PowerShell Enthusiasts!</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/01/01/calling-all-ohio-powershell-enthusiasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/01/01/calling-all-ohio-powershell-enthusiasts/</guid>
      <description>The Central Ohio Day of .NET is coming up (April 18th, 2009) and they’ve put out a request for speakers.&amp;#160; From their website:
  The Central Ohio Day of .NET is a joint venture between the Dayton .NET Developers Group, Central Ohio .NET Developers Group, Cincinnati SQL Server Users Group and the Cincinnati .NET Users Group.
Why don’t we get some PowerShell related sessions added to the lineup.&amp;#160; They said specifically that they are looking for introductory material on new technologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell Virtual User Group #8 Coming Up</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/01/01/powershell-virtual-user-group-08-coming-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/01/01/powershell-virtual-user-group-08-coming-up/</guid>
      <description>Marco Shaw has posted the details for the next PowerShell Virtual User Group.&amp;#160; Details can also be found on Marco’s blog, as well as other great content.
Keep 12 PM EST free on January 29th!&amp;#160; See you there!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>