<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Development on A Sysadmin, An SRE, and a DevOps Walk Into a Bar</title>
    <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/categories/development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Development on A Sysadmin, An SRE, and a DevOps Walk Into a Bar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://stevenmurawski.com/categories/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dear Devs,  Give Us The Tools.  K Thx</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/07/01/dear-devs-give-us-the-tools-k-thx/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/07/01/dear-devs-give-us-the-tools-k-thx/</guid>
      <description>I just finished listening to the latest Herding Code podcast (#52) where the hosts (K. Scott Allen, Kevin Dente, Scott Koon, and Jon Galloway) talked with Alan Stevens ( C# MVP and ASP Insider) and G. Andrew Duthie (author and Microsoft Developer Evangelist) about a debate that began on Twitter regarding “Real Software Development vs Microsoft Bubble Development”. What does that have to do with PowerShell and administrative tools? The specifics of their conversation don’t have a lot of relevance to administrators and scripters, but one of the directions that their conversation took really resonated with me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell in Azure</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/07/01/powershell-in-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/07/01/powershell-in-azure/</guid>
      <description>The July CTP release of the Windows Azure SDK contains a new sample project called PowerShellRole which demonstrates that PowerShell is available in the cloud!
Previous versions of the CTP have come with a sample Provider which you could use to access Azure storage (blobs, queues, and tables), but this actually provides demonstration of creating runspaces and executing pipelines in the cloud.
Now to see what version is running in the cloud!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More PowerShell on the Thirsty Developer</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/06/01/more-powershell-on-the-thirsty-developer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/06/01/more-powershell-on-the-thirsty-developer/</guid>
      <description>Larry Clarkin asked me back on the Thirsty Developer to continue talking about development and PowerShell.&amp;#160; We talked about creating cmdlets, hosting PowerShell, and a bit about Version 2.&amp;#160; Check it out here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turn Your Stored Procedures Into PowerShell Functions - MetaProgramming With PowerShell</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/04/01/turn-your-stored-procedures-into-powershell-functions-metaprogramming-with-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/04/01/turn-your-stored-procedures-into-powershell-functions-metaprogramming-with-powershell/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE: The script was moved to Google Code. The links in the post have been updated to reflect that. Or you can just go here&amp;hellip; http://code.google.com/p/poshcodegen/ I’ve been working on some data conversion at work, converting records from one system to a new system. I’ve built quite a library of SQL queries with PowerShell wrappers for dealing with data in the first system, but I don’t have the same luxury with the new system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft TechDays Virtual Event</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/03/01/microsoft-techdays-virtual-event/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/03/01/microsoft-techdays-virtual-event/</guid>
      <description>On April 1st, 2009, Microsoft is putting on a free 24 hour virtual event covering developer-related topics. There will be 95 live sessions provided via Live Meeting in the following tracks:
 Windows Development and Frameworks Windows Mobile Development Office and SharePoint Development Developer Tools, Languages &amp;amp; Practices Web Development &amp;amp; User Experience  PowerShell Community’s own Marco Shaw (MVP) will be presenting the ONLY PowerShell session:
  WIN300 Scripting the Microsoft .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cahoots! Rocks</title>
      <link>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/02/01/cahoots-rocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenmurawski.com/2009/02/01/cahoots-rocks/</guid>
      <description>Cahoots! is an open source project that provides a Question and Answer forum that is driven by community participation.&amp;#160; It also includes blogging, podcasting, and a knowledgebase functionality.&amp;#160;
Logins are managed via OpenID, so you don’t have to worry about managing additional login credentials.
Your capabilities to create content are driven by “esteem”, which is a metric for tracking the response to content you provide.&amp;#160; You can gain “esteem” by asking asking questions, posting blog entries, and having people follow your activities on the site.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>